A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Office Files of Nancy McCarthy FA530
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Office Files of Nancy McCarthy
Bulk, 1976-1989 1951-1989
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA530
1.2 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Ford Foundation
- American Unversity Field Staff, 1981 (Box 1)
- Association of American Colleges -- Washington DC, 1984 (Box 1)
- (CAL) Center for Applied Lingustics (1/6), 1958-1984 (Box 1)
- Center for Applied Lingustics (2/6), 1981 (Box 1)
- Center for Applied Lingustics (3/6), 1978-1982 (Box 1)
- Center for Applied Lingustics (4/6), 1981 (Box 1)
- Center for Applied Lingustics (5/6), 1982 (Box 1)
- Center for Applied Lingustics (6/6), 1976-1985 (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1985-Sep 1986 (Box 1)
- Daedalus, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- East European Refugees and the East European Fund, 1951-1980 (Box 1)
- Film on Latin America, 1981 (Box 1)
- Individual Awards, 1979 (Box 1)
- Intercultural Publications, 1954-1981 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- SSRC Tie off, Miscellaneous, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- Tie off, 1982 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- Veria, 1982 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- Notes on Programs at Universities funded by the Ford Foundation, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- Notes and Memoranda, 1967-1988 (Box 1)
- International Studies -- Program Development (Contacts), 1979-1987 (Box 1)
- International Tax Program, n.d. (Box 1)
- IREX, n.d. (Box 1)
- IREX, 1982 (Box 1)
- (ITR) International Training and Research -- Arts and Humanities (1/3), 1980 (Box 1)
- (ITR) International Training and Research -- Notes and memoranda (2/3), 1971 (Box 1)
- (ITR) International Training and Research -- Varia (3/3), 1978 (Box 1)
- Literacy and the HBC's -- General, 1984 (Box 1)
- Literacy and the HBC's -- Southern Education Foundation Summer Writing Workshop, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
- Literacy and the HBC's -- Trillin/Garwey, 1984 (Box 1)
- McCaughey, Robert A, 1978 (Box 1)
- Mid Decade Review, 1986 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1973-1989 (Box 1)
- Pittsburgh/LRDC -- Reading/Working File, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- President's Commission/Awards, 1976-1979 (Box 1)